snappages.com 2019-08-05

# SnapPages - Privacy

The purpose of this privacy policy is to explain in simple terms what personal data SnapPages collects, why we collect it, and what we do with it. We highly value the privacy of our users and want them to know that we are doing our best to keep their information safe and secure. Please take some time to read over the following document and contact us if you have any questions.

 **Why do we collect information?  **  
SnapPages is a collection of tools to help you build your own website. Information we gather is mainly used to help setup your account so that you can use our products and services. When you register for an account you become a "User". We do use some 3rd party services to provide ongoing support to our Users as well as tracking analytics and marketing efforts for Users and visitors.

  **What information do we collect?**  
When you sign up for an Account, we collect personally identifiable information including your first and last name, email address, and IP address. If you choose to upgrade your Account we will also collect your billing information as well.

 **What do we do with the information?**  
The main purpose of the personal information we collect is to provide our Users with ongoing support and to inform them of product and policy changes. A User's email address may be used by SnapPages to send out marketing material. These emails will always include an easy opt-out or "unsubscribe" link.

The IP address is used to help show the geographical information of our Users to better understand the trends of our customers. This information is only stored internally and is not used publicly or shared with a  3rd party.

The billing information (credit card number, address, etc.) that User's provide is used to pay for the products and services that SnapPages provides. This is all handled by our payment processor and is not directly stored or processed by SnapPages.

 **Information submitted by Users to SnapPages**  
Only upon User consent will the personal information of a User be shown to those people whom the User chooses. Except where a User might choose to include a full name in public information, a User's email address and full name will only be used in the following circumstances:

  * When we send notifications to the Member relating to his or her use of the SnapPages service or SnapPages website
  * If the customer so chooses, when we send regular notifications, updates or other news regarding SnapPages.

 **Information that Members do not submit to us**  
We use information relating to the server information, IP address, and browser-type.

 **Sharing of the Information SnapPages Gathers/Tracks**  
Except as explained above, or where you are expressly informed otherwise, we do not sell, rent, share, trade or give away any of your personal information, unless required by law or for the protection of your Membership. However, in the future SnapPages may share profile information and aggregate usage information in 

_a non-personally identifiable manner_

with advertisers and other third parties in order to present to Users of the SnapPages targeted advertising, products and services. In such situations we will never disclose information that would personally identify you such as email address, name, or phone number.

 **Links and other Sites referred to on SnapPages**  
This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by SnapPages through the SnapPages website. SnapPages is not responsible for any links referred to within SnapPages and their Privacy Policies.

 **Use of Cookies**  
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping and user experience purposes. We use cookies on SnapPages. However, we do not and will not use cookies to collect private information from any Member or other user of SnapPages which they did not intentionally submit to us, other than as stated in this Privacy Policy.

We use both "session ID cookies" and "persistent cookies." We use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file; however, please note that, if you reject cookies or disable cookies in your web browser, you may not be able to use portions of SnapPages.

 **Change of Ownership**  
In the event that SnapPages is involved in a bankruptcy or insolvency, acquisition, merger, sale of assets or similar transactions, your information will be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. You will be notified via email of any change in ownership or uses of your personal data.

 **Changes in Our Privacy Policy**  
If we change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our web site so Users of the SnapPages website are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If we are going to use users’ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify those Users via email or by placing a prominent notice on our website.

 **Security**  
The SnapPages account of every user is password-protected. SnapPages takes every precaution to protect the information of the Users. We use industry standard measures to protect all information that is stored on our servers and within our database. We limit the access to this information to those employees who need access to perform their job function such as our customer service personnel. If you have any questions about the security at our website, please contact us.

 **Deletion of Personal Data**  
SnapPages will generally keep your information on it's servers for at least 1 year after a cancellation because many times users will temporarily shut down their website but want the option of enabling it again at another time. At any time if a User wishes for their personal data to be removed, they may contact SnapPages and we will promptly do this for them.

 **Members and Users Located Outside of the United States of America**  
We have made an effort to protect the personal information of all users of SnapPages, and to the extent applicable, we attempt to comply with local data protection and consumer rights laws. If you are unsure whether this privacy policy is in conflict with the applicable local rules where you are located, you should not submit your personal information to SnapPages. 

**Intercom**  
SnapPages uses Intercom to offer support to our customers and notify users of new features. We also use Intercom to track information about our customers and leads. Personally identifiable information, including name, email address, and location is submitted to Intercom’s servers and saved there when a user registers for a SnapPages account. The option to subscribe to notification is made possible through the use of JavaScript and cookies. Information obtained via the cookies and / or the JavaScript widget, including IP address, browser version, OS version, activity data, usage information, transaction information and plan details is transferred to Intercom’s servers and saved there. Other information, including IP address, browser & OS version, and timestamps, is submitted to Intercom when a user loads resources embedded in, or a link contained an email sent through Intercom.

You can learn more about Intercom’s privacy policy at:  
<https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy>

 **Google Analytics**  
The SnapPages website uses Google Analytics. This is a service of Google that provides to track website access, and enables to see how visitors use our site so we can make improvements. This is made possible through the use of cookies. The data gathered from cookies is transferred to Google servers and saved there. We are able to then view this data in various reports.

Visitors can prevent the placement of Google Analytics cookies on their computer through the settings on their web browser. If this happens, we can't guarantee that all the functions of our website will be available to you.

You can find further information about Google’s privacy policy at:  
<https://policies.google.com/> And <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/>

**Facebook**  
SnapPages uses various Facebook integrations to track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. When a user is logged into a Facebook account and they visit the SnapPages website, Facebook will additionally receive a notification of this. Facebook collects this information, and it's possible that they could associate it with the Facebook account. This also applies to the “Like” button and the Facebook comment forms. Visitors can prevent this from happening by logging out of Facebook prior to visiting the SnapPages website.

You can find further information about Facebook's privacy policy at:  
<https://facebook.com/about/privacy>

 **Braintree**  
SnapPages uses Braintree as it's primary payment processor. The following data is sent, and stored by them:

  * Your name and email address
  * Your payment method (credit card number, expiry date, CVC)
  * Your IP address, and the time and date of your transaction

If you wish to have your information removed, you may cancel your SnapPages account and request that we delete all your customer information.

You can find further information about Braintree's privacy policy at:  
<https://www.braintreepayments.com/en-de/legal/braintree-privacy-policy>

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, SnapPages’ privacy practices, or your dealings with SnapPages, please contact us.
